<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<template version="3.2" class="template_presentation" view="view_presentation">
	<section id="meta-data">
		<notes id="page-description"/>
		<notes id="programmed-events"/>
		<notes id="programming-options"/>
	</section>
	<configuration id="general_settings">
		<settings id="customEvents" datatype="BOOLEAN" value="true"/>
		<settings id="setComplete" datatype="LIST" value="CUSTOM"/>
	</configuration>
	<graphic id="background" x="0" y="0" width="795" height="533" behavior="LOCK_XY|LOCK_SIZE" style="PLAIN" visible="true" fx="SHOW" hidefx="HIDE" disabled="true">
		<file play="false" bytes="5827" startpos="1">wizard.jpg</file>
		<eventlist>
			<event type="CLICK" result="DISABLE" target="_self" result_param=""/>
		</eventlist>
	</graphic>
	<text id="title" x="37" y="35" width="456" height="" autosize="H" style="WIZARD_TITLE" visible="true" fx="SHOW" hidefx="HIDE">
		<content translate="true">Reference Citations</content>
	</text>
	<text id="references" x="37" y="65" width="697" height="352" autosize="" style="WIZARD_TEXT" visible="true" fx="SHOW" hidefx="HIDE" scroll="AUTO">
		<content translate="true">&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Adam, E., Klimes-Dougan, B., &amp; Gunnar, M. (2007). Social regulation of the adrenocortical response to stress in infants, children, and adolescents: Implications for psychopathology and education. &lt;I&gt;Human behavior, learning, and the developing brain: Atypical development&lt;/I&gt;, 264–304. New York, NY: Guilford Press.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Ames, L., &amp; Ilg, F. (1964). The developmental point of view with special reference to the principle of reciprocal neuromotor interweaving. &lt;I&gt;Journal of Genetic Psychology, 105&lt;/I&gt;, 195–209.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Aslin, R. N., Pisoni, D. B., &amp; Jusczyk, P.W. (1983). Auditory development and speech perception in infancy. In P. H. Mussen (Series Ed.), M. M. Haith, &amp; J. J. Campos (Vol. Eds.), &lt;I&gt;Handbook of child psychology: Vol. 2. Infancy and developmental psychobiology&lt;/I&gt; (4th ed., pp. 573–687). New York, NY: Wiley. &lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Belsky, J., &amp; Pluess, M. (2009). Beyond Diathesis-Stress: Differential Susceptibility to Environmental Influences. &lt;I&gt;Psychological Bulletin, 135&lt;/I&gt;(6), 885–908.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Blair, C., &amp; Razza, R. P. (2007). Relating effortful control, executive function, and false belief understanding to emerging math and literacy ability in kindergarten. &lt;I&gt;Child Development, 78&lt;/I&gt;(2), 647–663.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Bowlby, J. (1969). Attachment and loss: Volume 1. &lt;I&gt;Attachment&lt;/I&gt;. New York, NY: Basic Books.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Carey, W.B. (1998). Teaching parents about infant temperament. &lt;I&gt;PEDIATRICS, 102&lt;/I&gt;(5), 1311–1316.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Cole, P. M., Armstrong, L. M., &amp; Pemberton, C. K. (2010). The role of language in the development of emotion regulation. In S. Calkins and M. Bell (Eds) &lt;I&gt;Child development at the intersection of emotion and cognition: Human brain development &lt;/I&gt;(pp. 59–77). Washington DC, US: American Psychological Association.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Cole, P. M., Dennis, T. A., Smith-Simon, K. E., &amp; Cohen, L. H. (2009). Preschoolers' emotion regulation strategy understanding: Relations with emotion socialization and child self-regulation. &lt;I&gt;Social Development, 18&lt;/I&gt;, 324–352.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Emde, R., Plomin, R., Robinson, J., &amp; Corley, R. (1992) Temperament, emotion, and cognitive at fourteen months: The MacArthur Longitudinal Twin Study. &lt;I&gt;Child Development, 63&lt;/I&gt;(6), 1437–1455.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Eisenberg, N., Smith, C. L., Sadovsky, A., &amp; Spinrad, T. L. (2004). Effortful control: Relations with emotion regulation, adjustment, and socialization in childhood. In R. F. Baumeister &amp; K. D. Vohs (Eds.), Handbook of self-regulation: &lt;I&gt;Research, theory, and applications&lt;/I&gt; (pp. 259–282). New York, NY: Guildford Press.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Fentress, J. C., &amp; McLeod, P. J. (1986). Motor patterns in development. In Blass, E. M. (Ed.) Handbook of behavioral neurobiology, 8. &lt;I&gt;Developmental psychology and developmental neurobiology.&lt;/I&gt; New York, NY: Plenum.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Gunner, M. R. &amp; Donzella, B. (2002). Social regulation of the cortisol levels in early human development. &lt;I&gt;Psychoneuroendocrinology, 27&lt;/I&gt;, 199–220.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Gunnar, M., &amp; Fisher, P. (2006). Bringing basic research on early experience and stress neurobiology to bear on preventive interventions for neglected and maltreated children. &lt;I&gt;Development and Psychopathology, 18&lt;/I&gt;(3), 651–677.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Gunnar, M., &amp; Vazquez, D. (2001). Low cortisol and a flattening of expected daytime rhythm: Potential indices of risk in human development. &lt;I&gt;Development and Psychopathology, 13&lt;/I&gt;(3), 515–538.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Hirsh-Pasek, K., &amp; Golinkoff, R. M. (2003). &lt;I&gt;Einstein never used flash cards: How our children really learn and why they need to play more and memorize less&lt;/I&gt;. Emmaus, PA: Rodale Books.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Howse, R. B., Lange, G., Farran, D.C., &amp; Boyles, C. D. (2003). Motivation and seflregulation as predictors of achievement in economically disadvantaged young children. &lt;I&gt;The Journal of Experimental Education, 71&lt;/I&gt;, 151–174.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Kaufman, J., Birmaher, B., Perel, J., Dahl, R., Moreci, P., Nelson, B., et al. (1997). The corticotropin-releasing hormone challenge in depressed abused, depressed nonabused, and normal control children.&lt;I&gt; Biological Psychiatry, 42&lt;/I&gt;(8), 669–679.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Kertes, D., Donzella, B., Talge, N., Garvin, M., Van Ryzin, M., &amp; Gunnar, M. (2009). Inhibited temperament and parent emotional availability differentially predict young children's cortisol responses to novel social and nonsocial events. &lt;I&gt;Developmental Psychobiology, 51&lt;/I&gt;(7), 521–532.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Kochanska, G., Aksan, N., &amp; Joy, M. E. (2007). Children's fearfulness as a moderator of parenting in early socialization: Two longitudinal studies. &lt;I&gt;Developmental Psychology, 43&lt;/I&gt;(1), 222–237.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Kochanska, G., Murray, K., &amp; Coy, K. C. (1997). Inhibitory control as a contributor to conscience in childhood: From toddler to early school age. &lt;I&gt;Child Development, 68&lt;/I&gt;, 263–277.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Lengua, L. J., &amp; Long, A. C. (2002). The role of emotionality and self-regulation in the appraisal-coping process: Tests of direct and moderating effects. &lt;I&gt;Journal of Applied Developmental Psychology, 23&lt;/I&gt;, 471–493.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Meltzoff, A. N., &amp; Borton, R. W. (1979). Intermodal matching by human neonates. &lt;I&gt;Nature, 282&lt;/I&gt;, 403–404.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Nachmias, M., Gunnar, M. R., Mangelsdorf, S., Parritz, R., &amp; Buss, K. A. (1996). Behavioral inhibition and stress reactivity: Moderating role of attachment security. &lt;I&gt;Child Development, 67&lt;/I&gt;(2), 508–522.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;National Scientific Council on the Developing Child (2005). &lt;I&gt;Excessive stress disrupts the architecture of the developing brain: Working paper No. 3.&lt;/I&gt; Retrieved from http://www.developingchild.harvard.edu.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Peck, J. E. (1995). Development of hearing. Part III. Postnatal development. &lt;I&gt;Journal of the American Academy of Audiology, 6&lt;/I&gt;, 113–123.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Pollak, S. D., Cicchetti, D., &amp; Klorman, R. (1998). Stress, Memory, and Emotion: Developmental considerations from the study of child maltreatment. &lt;I&gt;Development and Psychopathology, 10&lt;/I&gt;, 811–828.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Ponitz, C. C., McClelland, M. M., Matthews, J. S., &amp; Morrison, F. J. (2009). A structured observation of behavioral self-regulation and its contribution to kindergarten outcomes. &lt;I&gt;Developmental Psychology, 45&lt;/I&gt;, 605–619.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Robin, D. J., Berthier, N. E., &amp; Clifton, R. K. (1996). Infants' predictive reaching for moving objects in the dark. &lt;I&gt;Developmental Psychology, 32&lt;/I&gt;, 824–835.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Rothbart, M. K., &amp; Bates, J. (2006). Temperament. In N. Eisenberg, W. Damon, &amp; L. M. Richard (Eds.), &lt;I&gt;Handbook of child psychology: Vol. 3, Social, emotional, and personality development&lt;/I&gt; (6th ed.) (pp. 99–166). Hobokeen, NJ: John Willey &amp; Sons Inc.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Rothbart, M. K., &amp; Derryberry, D. (1981). Development of individual differences in temperament. In M.E. Lamb &amp; A.L. Brown (Eds.). &lt;I&gt;Advances in developmental psychology&lt;/I&gt; (Vo.1, pp. 37-86). Hillsdale, NJ: Erlbaum.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Ryan, R. M., Connell, J. P., &amp; Grolnick, W. S. (1992). When achievement is not intrinsically motivated: A theory and assessment of self-regulation in school. In A. K. Boggiano &amp; T. S. Pittman (Eds.), &lt;I&gt;Achievement and motivation: A social-developmental perspective &lt;/I&gt;(pp.167–188). New York: Cambridge University Press.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Shelov, S. P. (Editor-in-Chief). (2009). Caring for Your Baby and Young Child: Birth to Age 5. &lt;I&gt;The American Association of Pediatrics&lt;/I&gt; (5th ed.). New York, NY: Bantam Books.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Steiner, J. E. (1979). Human facial expressions in response to taste and smell stimulation. In H. W. Reese, H. W., &amp; Lipsitt, L. P. (Eds.), &lt;I&gt;Advances in child development and behavior&lt;/I&gt;. Orlando, FL: Academic Press. &lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Thomas, A. &amp; Chess, S. (1977). &lt;I&gt;Temperament and development.&lt;/I&gt; New York, NY: Brunner/Mazel.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Thompson, R. A., Brown, K., Grossmann, K. E., Gunnar, M. R., Heinrichs, M., Keller, H., O'Connor, T. G., Spangler, G., Voland, E., &amp; Wang, S. (2005). Group report: Early social attachment and its consequences. In C. S. Carter, L. Ahnert, K. E. Grossmann, S. B. Hardy, M.E. Lamb, S.W. Porges &amp; N. -Axis (Eds.), From the 92nd Dahlem Workshop Report, &lt;I&gt;Attachment and Bonding: A New Synthesis&lt;/I&gt; (pp. 349–383). Cambridge, UK: MIT Press. &lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;Tronick, E. (1998). Dyadically expanded states of consciousness and the process of therapeutic change. &lt;I&gt;Infant Mental Health Journal, 19&lt;/I&gt;(3), 290–299.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;White, B., Gunnar, M., Larson, M., Donzella, B. &amp; Barr, R. (2003). Behavioral and physiological responsivity, sleep, and patterns of daily cortisol production in infants with and without colic. &lt;I&gt;Annual progress in child psychiatry and child development: 2000–2001, 73–100&lt;/I&gt;. New York, NY: Brunner-Routledge.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P ALIGN="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</content>
	</text>
	<graphic id="print" x="647" y="430" width="" height="" behavior="" style="CONTROLS" visible="true" fx="SHOW" hidefx="HIDE">
		<file play="false" bytes="3602" startpos="1" duration="23">btn_print.swf</file>
		<eventlist>
			<event type="CLICK" result="CALL_FUNCTION" target="PAGE" result_param="printWizard();"/>
		</eventlist>
	</graphic>
</template>
